<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>The Evaluating Model Development and Criterion Validity Test on Knowledge Activities: Kant Epistemological Perspective</title>
<publication-date>2004-09-01T00:00:00-07:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<email>el239@cornell.edu</email>
<institution>Korea University, School of Business Administration</institution>
<lname>Lee</lname>
<fname>Eul-Teo</fname>
</author>
</authors>
<keywords>
<keyword>Knowledge</keyword>
<keyword>Kant Epistemology</keyword>
<keyword>Criterion validity</keyword>
<keyword>Knowledge based working activities</keyword>
<keyword>Experience knowledge</keyword>
<keyword>Theoretical knowledge</keyword>
<keyword>Conceptualization</keyword>
<keyword>Integrated judgment</keyword>
<keyword>Individual knowledge creation</keyword>
<keyword>Knowledge sharing</keyword>
<keyword>Group concept creation</keyword>
<keyword>HR based organizational innovation</keyword>
</keywords>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this study is to develop the evaluating model of knowledge-based working activities(KBWA) on individuals and empirically explore the criterion validity of it. Particular attention is paid to the theoretical development and operationalization of KBWA evaluating model in terms of Kant epistemology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The KBWA evaluating model consists of three level knowledge activities, i.e. job, group, organizational related knowledge activities. These activities as predictive variables on knowledge performance have positively outcomes (dependent variables) to examine criterion validity. Job-related activities include experience knowledge, theoretical knowledge, conceptualization, integrated judgment, and individual knowledge creation. Group-related activities are knowledge suggestion to achieve team goal and knowledge sharing with team members. Organization-related activities of individuals are organizational knowledge diffusion using various IT tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For validity test of KBWA, first, this study was conducted interview on 75 SME in HR field. Second, empirical tests the structural equation modeling using 413 questionnaire survey data from a leading 11 Informational Technology Firms. Three major LISREL results have emerged from the study. First, job-related activities are positively and significantly correlated to expected outcome variables which are task performance and intellectual stimuli toward co-worker. Second, group-related activities are strongly positive correlated to group-level knowledge creation and group performance. Third, Organizational knowledge diffusion of individuals are not significant effect on HR based organizational innovation. This research has conclusively shown that KBWA evaluating instruments can be considered predictive validation with regard to job and group related knowledge activities on individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the findings, managerial implications are derived. Suggestions for future research also follow.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/intlvf/4</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1001&amp;amp;context=intlvf&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>4</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>1001</articleid>
<submission-date>2005-03-28T14:42:32-08:00</submission-date>
<native-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/context/intlvf/article/1001/type/native/viewcontent</native-url>
<publication-title>Visiting Fellow Working Papers</publication-title>
<context-key>52275</context-key>
<submission-path>intlvf/4</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="comments" type="string">
<value>The paper is available in Korean only.</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2004-09-01T00:00:00-07:00</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>