<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>Employee Voice, Human Resource Practices, and Quit Rates: Evidence from the Telecommunications Industry</title>
<publication-date>2001-02-01T00:00:00-08:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<email>rb41@cornell.edu</email>
<institution>Cornell University</institution>
<lname>Batt</lname>
<fname>Rosemary</fname>
</author>
<author>
<institution>Penn State University</institution>
<lname>Colvin</lname>
<fname>Alexander</fname>
</author>
<author>
<institution>Rutgers University</institution>
<lname>Keefe</lname>
<fname>Jeffrey</fname>
</author>
</authors>
<keywords>
<keyword>organization</keyword>
<keyword>practice</keyword>
<keyword>work</keyword>
<keyword>HR</keyword>
<keyword>human resource</keyword>
<keyword>employee</keyword>
<keyword>market</keyword>
<keyword>industrial relations</keyword>
<keyword>union</keyword>
<keyword>teams</keyword>
<keyword>pay</keyword>
</keywords>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we examine the predictors of aggregate quit rates at the establishment level. We draw on strategic human resource and industrial relations theory to identify the sets of employee voice mechanisms and human resource practices that are likely to predict quit rates. With respect to alternative voice mechanisms, we find that union representation significantly predicts lower quit rates after controlling for compensation and a wide range of other human resource practices that may be affected by collective bargaining. Direct participation via offline problem-solving groups and self-directed teams is significantly negatively related to quit rates,but non-union dispute resolution procedures are not. In addition, higher relative wages and internal promotion policies significantly predict lower quit rates, while contingent staffing, electronic monitoring, and variable pay predict significantly higher rates.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cahrswp/67</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1066&amp;amp;context=cahrswp&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>67</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>1066</articleid>
<submission-date>2005-11-01T11:09:13-08:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>CAHRS Working Paper Series</publication-title>
<context-key>115457</context-key>
<submission-path>cahrswp/67</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="comments" type="string">
<value>&lt;B&gt;Suggested Citation&lt;/B&gt;&lt;BR&gt;Batt, R., Colvin, A. &amp; Keefe, J. (2001). &lt;I&gt;Employee voice, human resource practices, and quit rates: Evidence from the telecommunications industry&lt;/I&gt;    (CAHRS Working Paper #01-04). Ithaca, NY: Cornell University, School of Industrial and Labor Relations, Center for Advanced Human Resource Studies. &lt;BR&gt;http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cahrswp/67</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2001-02-01T00:00:00-08:00</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>