<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>In The Trenches At The Talent Wars: An Examination Of Competitive Interaction For Human Resources In The Software Industry</title>
<publication-date>2003-02-01T00:00:00-08:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<email>tmg13@byu.edu</email>
<institution>Brigham Young University</institution>
<lname>Gardner</lname>
<fname>Timothy</fname>
<mname>M.</mname>
</author>
</authors>
<keywords>
<keyword>organization</keyword>
<keyword>performance</keyword>
<keyword>research</keyword>
<keyword>firm</keyword>
<keyword>employee</keyword>
<keyword>HRS</keyword>
<keyword>management</keyword>
<keyword>human resource</keyword>
</keywords>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;In this study, I attempted to extend strategic human resource management theory by developing and testing a model of inter-firm competition for human resources. Using the phenomenon of talent raiding as a vehicle to test the model, I examined how degree of threat and firm capability affected firms’ propensities to respond to rivals’ actions. Results suggest that attributes of the raiding firm, attributes of the raided human capital, and attributes of the target firm were associated with target firms’ propensity to defend or retaliate in response to a successful talent raid. The findings have implications for a tactical theory of human resource management and the origins of intra-firm differences in human resource systems.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cahrswp/28</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1027&amp;amp;context=cahrswp&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>28</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>1027</articleid>
<submission-date>2005-10-20T11:32:03-07:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>CAHRS Working Paper Series</publication-title>
<context-key>111387</context-key>
<submission-path>cahrswp/28</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="comments" type="string">
<value>&lt;B&gt;Suggested Citation&lt;/B&gt;&lt;BR&gt;Gardner, T. M.  (2003). &lt;I&gt; In the trenches at the talent wars: An examination of competitive interaction for human resources in the software industry &lt;/I&gt;  (CAHRS Working Paper #03-05). Ithaca, NY: Cornell University, School of Industrial and Labor Relations, Center for Advanced Human Resource Studies. &lt;BR&gt;http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cahrswp/28</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2003-02-01T00:00:00-08:00</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>