<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>A Test of Competitive Labor Market Theory:  The Wage Structure among Elder Care Assistants in the South of England</title>
<publication-date>2004-04-01T00:00:00-08:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<institution>University College London</institution>
<lname>Machin</lname>
<fname>Stephen</fname>
</author>
<author>
<institution>London School of Economics</institution>
<lname>Manning</lname>
<fname>Alan</fname>
</author>
</authors>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;This paper examines the structure of wages in a very specific labor market: care assistants in residential homes for the elderly on England’s “sunshine coast.” This sector corresponds closely to economists’ notion of what should be a competitive labor market, both because it has a large number of small firms undertaking a very homogeneous activity in a concentrated geographical area, and because the workers are neither unionized nor covered by any minimum wage legislation, so that there are effectively no external constraints on the wage-setting process. The authors find that the wage structure deviates in important respects from what would be expected in a competitive labor market. In particular, wage dispersion is small within firms, but large between firms; and the wage dispersion that is present does not seem to be closely related to workers’ productivity-related characteristics. A test rejects the hypothesis that unobserved labor quality can explain these findings.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/ilrreview/vol57/iss3/3</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1074&amp;amp;context=ilrreview&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>3</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>1074</articleid>
<submission-date>2005-07-12T07:08:05-07:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>ILR Review</publication-title>
<context-key>82995</context-key>
<submission-path>ilrreview/vol57/iss3/3</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="peer_reviewed" type="boolean">
<value>true</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2004-04-01T00:00:00-08:00</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>