<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>Effects of Disability, Gender, and Level of Supervision on Ratings of Job Applicants</title>
<publication-date>2001-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<email>bb92@cornell.edu</email>
<institution>Cornell University</institution>
<lname>Bell</lname>
<fname>Bradford</fname>
<mname>S.</mname>
</author>
<author>
<institution>The Wharton School, University of Pennsylvania</institution>
<lname>Klein</lname>
<fname>Katherine</fname>
<mname>J.</mname>
</author>
</authors>
<keywords>
<keyword>Disability</keyword>
<keyword>supervision</keyword>
<keyword>applicant</keyword>
<keyword>application</keyword>
<keyword>gender</keyword>
<keyword>disabled</keyword>
<keyword>job</keyword>
<keyword>employment</keyword>
<keyword>discrimination</keyword>
<keyword>handicap</keyword>
</keywords>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Using ratings of hypothetical job applicants with and without a disability obtained from both fulltime workers (n = 88) and undergraduates (n = 98), we examined the effects of disability (paraplegia, epilepsy, clinical depression, or non-disabled), gender, and nature of the job (supervisory or non-supervisory) on five job-relevant dependent measures. Contrary to our hypothesis, applicants with a disability were rated significantly higher in activity and potency than applicants without a disability. Further, also contrary to our predictions, gender and job type did not moderate the relationship between disability and applicant ratings.  Post-hoc analyses revealed a significant gender by job type interaction; female applicants were viewed as more qualified than male applicants for the non-supervisory position, but the male applicants were viewed as more qualified than female applicants for the supervisory position. We use the flexible correction model (Wegener &amp; Petty, 1997) to explicate the findings.  Limitations and implications for future research on attitudes toward individuals with disabilities are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/hrpubs/10</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1009&amp;amp;context=hrpubs&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>10</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>1009</articleid>
<submission-date>2005-06-21T08:45:46-07:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>Faculty Publications - Human Resource Studies</publication-title>
<context-key>81173</context-key>
<submission-path>hrpubs/10</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="comments" type="string">
<value>&lt;B&gt;Suggested Citation&lt;/B&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
Bell, B. S., &amp; Klein, K. J. (2001). Effects of disability, gender, and job level on ratings of job applicants. Retrieved [insert date], from Cornell University, School of Industrial and Labor Relations site:&lt;BR&gt;
http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/hrpubs/10/&lt;p&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Required Publisher Statement&lt;/B&gt; &lt;BR&gt;
This article may not exactly replicate the final version published in the APA journal. It is not the copy of record.  Final paper published as Bell, B. S., &amp; Klein, K. J. (2001). Effects of disability, gender, and job level on ratings of job applicants. &lt;a href=http://www.apa.org/journals/rep/ &gt; &lt;i&gt;Rehabilitation Psychology&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;i&gt;46&lt;/i&gt;, 229-246.</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2001-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>