<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>Nursing Against The Odds: How Health Care Cost Cutting, Media Stereotypes, and Medical Hubris Undermine Nurses and Patient Care</title>
<publication-date>2005-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<lname>Gordon</lname>
<fname>Suzanne</fname>
</author>
</authors>
<keywords>
<keyword>nurse</keyword>
<keyword>doctor</keyword>
<keyword>work</keyword>
<keyword>medical</keyword>
<keyword>disruptive</keyword>
<keyword>system</keyword>
<keyword>hospital</keyword>
<keyword>care</keyword>
<keyword>intern</keyword>
<keyword>patient</keyword>
<keyword>cancer</keyword>
<keyword>pain</keyword>
<keyword>physicians</keyword>
<keyword>teaching</keyword>
</keywords>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;In the United States and throughout the industrialized world, just as the population of older and sicker patients is about to explode, there is a major shortage of nurses. In Nursing against the Odds, one of North America’s leading health care journalists draws on in-depth interviews, research studies, and extensive firsthand reporting to help readers better understand the myriad causes of and possible solutions to the current crisis. To promote better care, Gordon calls for a broad agenda that includes safer staffing, improved scheduling, and other policy changes that would give nurses a greater voice at work. She explores how doctors and nurses can collaborate more effectively and what medical and nursing education must do to foster such cooperation. Finally, Gordon outlines ways in which RNs can successfully take their case to the public while campaigning for health care system reform that actually funds necessary nursing care.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/books/7</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1006&amp;amp;context=books&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>7</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>1006</articleid>
<submission-date>2005-09-20T07:46:59-07:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>Book Samples</publication-title>
<context-key>99875</context-key>
<submission-path>books/7</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="comments" type="string">
<value>The abstract, table of contents, and first twenty-five pages are published with permission from the Cornell University Press. For ordering information, please visit the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cornellpress.cornell.edu&quot; &gt;Cornell University Press&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;BR&gt;http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/books/7/</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2005-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>