<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>Organization-wide Broad-based Incentives: Rational Theory and Evidence</title>
<publication-date>2002-09-04T00:00:00-07:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<institution>State University of New York at Albany</institution>
<lname>Marler</lname>
<fname>Janet</fname>
<mname>H.</mname>
</author>
<author>
<institution>Cornell University</institution>
<lname>Milkovich</lname>
<fname>George</fname>
<mname>T.</mname>
</author>
<author>
<email>yoshio.yanadori@unisa.edu.au</email>
<institution>Cornell University</institution>
<lname>Yanadori</lname>
<fname>Yoshio</fname>
</author>
</authors>
<keywords>
<keyword>firms</keyword>
<keyword>compensation</keyword>
<keyword>performance</keyword>
<keyword>stock</keyword>
<keyword>incentives</keyword>
<keyword>variable pay</keyword>
</keywords>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Despite the widespread use of incentive pay, there is limited evidence about what factors influence its organization-wide, broad-based application. This study uses data from three sources and multiple levels, including a unique data set of the total compensation of individual employees in 104 firms over a four-year period (1997-2000), and theoretically and empirically examines the use of bonuses and stock options in organization-wide applications. We examine the efficacy of three main rational theories, principal-agency, positivist agency and contingency theories, which are based on the premise that incentives are related to performance. At the individual level we identify two determinants: type of job and level within the hierarchy and four determinants at the organizational level: performance, risk, size, and strategy. Our results indicate that the factors derived from the three theories provide a limited explanation for the variation in the use of broad-based incentives within and across organizations.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cahrswp/46</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1045&amp;amp;context=cahrswp&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>46</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>1045</articleid>
<submission-date>2005-10-25T12:39:31-07:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>CAHRS Working Paper Series</publication-title>
<context-key>112481</context-key>
<submission-path>cahrswp/46</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="comments" type="string">
<value>&lt;B&gt;Suggested Citation&lt;/B&gt;&lt;BR&gt; Marler, J. H.,  Milkovich, G. T. &amp; Yanadori, Y. (2002). &lt;I&gt; Organization-wide broad-based incentives: Rational theory and evidence  &lt;/I&gt;    (CAHRS Working Paper #02-05). Ithaca, NY: Cornell University, School of Industrial and Labor Relations, Center for Advanced Human Resource Studies. &lt;BR&gt;http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cahrswp/46</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2002-09-04T00:00:00-07:00</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>