<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>Women of Color: Their Employment in the Private Sector</title>
<publication-date>2003-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<lname>Equal Employment Opportunity Commission</lname>
<fname>U.S.</fname>
</author>
</authors>
<keywords>
<keyword>women</keyword>
<keyword>minority</keyword>
<keyword>employment</keyword>
<keyword>African American</keyword>
<keyword>Hispanic</keyword>
<keyword>work</keyword>
<keyword>Equal Employment Opportunity Commission</keyword>
<keyword>race</keyword>
<keyword>industry</keyword>
<keyword>ethnicity</keyword>
<keyword>private</keyword>
<keyword>sector</keyword>
</keywords>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;This examination of the employment status of minority women or women of color relies primarily on the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission&#39;s (EEOC) EEO-1 report. Characteristics of employment are examined from five different perspectives: total employment, employment by job group, employment of officials and managers, the movement of women from white collar to management positions and per capita charge rates by industry. Among the conclusions included in the report: race/ethnicity and industry both have an effect on per capita charge rates; firms in Engineering and Management Services are least likely to be the subject of a charge by each of the minority groups of women, except Asian women; Automotive Dealers and Service Stations is consistently ranked among the industries with the highest per capital charge rates; Construction-based industries, such as Special Trade Contractors and General Building Contractors, have high per capita charge rates for both African American women and Hispanic women. The highest ranked industry with highest level of per capita charges by Asian women is Apparel and Other Textile Products and for Native American women it is Social Services.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/key_workplace/88</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1089&amp;amp;context=key_workplace&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>88</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>1089</articleid>
<submission-date>2005-02-16T07:06:03-08:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>Federal Publications</publication-title>
<context-key>44334</context-key>
<submission-path>key_workplace/88</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="comments" type="string">
<value>&lt;b&gt;Suggested Citation&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;:  U.S. Equal Employment Opportunity Commission. (2003). Women of Color: Their Employment in the Private Sector. Washington, DC: Author.
http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/key_workplace/88/ &lt;p&gt;</value>
</field>
<field name="institute" type="string">
<value>EEOC</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2003-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>