<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>Do Wages Rise with Job Seniority?  A Reassessment</title>
<publication-date>2005-04-01T00:00:00-08:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<institution>Yale University</institution>
<lname>Altonji</lname>
<fname>Joseph</fname>
<mname>G</mname>
</author>
<author>
<institution>University of Cincinnati</institution>
<lname>Williams</lname>
<fname>Nicolas</fname>
</author>
</authors>
<keywords>
<keyword>job seniority</keyword>
<keyword>returns to tenure</keyword>
<keyword>tenure and wages</keyword>
</keywords>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;The authors provide new estimates of the return to job seniority using a dataset similar to that employed in Joseph Altonji and Robert Shakotko, “Do Wages Rise with Job Seniority?” Review of Economic Studies (1987) and Robert Topel, “Specific Capital, Mobility, and Wages,” Journal of Political Economy (1991). They consider the strengths and weaknesses of these studies’ treatment of economy-wide trends, their dating conventions for tenure and wages, their handling of wage observations that might span multiple jobs, and their estimation approaches. Re-estimation points to an effect of ten years of tenure on the log wage equal to .11, which is above the preferred estimate of Altonji and Shakotko but far below that of Topel. Changes in earnings distributions and in the employment relationship motivate the examination of more recent data. Perhaps surprisingly, the return to tenure has probably increased over time.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/ilrreview/vol58/iss3/4</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1131&amp;amp;context=ilrreview&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>4</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>1131</articleid>
<submission-date>2005-07-13T10:41:49-07:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>ILR Review</publication-title>
<context-key>83212</context-key>
<submission-path>ilrreview/vol58/iss3/4</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="acknowledgements" type="string">
<value>The authors thank Lanny Arvan, Paul Devereux, Randall Filer, Daniel Hamermesh, Bruce Meyer, Gary Solon, participants in seminars at the 1995 Econometric Society Winter Meetings, 1997 Society of Labor Economics Annual Meetings, the Bureau of Labor Statistics, the University of Michigan, the National Bureau of Economic Research, Northwestern University, and Ohio State University, and participants in the Ashenfelter Festschrift conference at Princeton University for helpful comments.  Without implying any endorsement of our analysis and conclusions, we give special thanks to Robert Topel for comments on a previous draft of the paper and for graciously providing us with a set of computer programs that greatly aided our research and to Paul Devereux for assisting us with the &quot;full PSID sample&quot; analyzed in the paper.  We also thank Tecla Loup, Kate McGonagle, and Robert Shoeni for assistance with the PSID data.  Finally, Altonji thanks Orley Ashenfelter for providing support and inspiration over many, many years.  This research was supported by the Institute for Policy Research, Northwestern University, and the National Science Foundation under grant SES-0112533.</value>
</field>
<field name="peer_reviewed" type="boolean">
<value>true</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2005-04-01T00:00:00-08:00</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>