<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>Nobody&#39;s Home: Candid Reflections of a Nursing Home Aide</title>
<publication-date>2005-01-12T00:00:00-08:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<lname>Gass</lname>
<fname>Thomas</fname>
<mname>Edward</mname>
</author>
</authors>
<keywords>
<keyword>nursing home</keyword>
<keyword>work</keyword>
<keyword>people</keyword>
<keyword>family</keyword>
<keyword>care</keyword>
<keyword>resident</keyword>
<keyword>nurse</keyword>
<keyword>aide</keyword>
</keywords>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;After caring for his mother at the end of her life, Thomas Edward Gass felt drawn to serve the elderly. He took a job as a nursing home aide but was not prepared for the reality that he found at his new place of employment, a for-profit long-term-care facility. In a book that is by turns chilling and graphic, poignant and funny, Gass describes America’s system of warehousing its oldest citizens.   With Americans living longer than ever before, elder care is among the fastest growing occupations. This book makes clear that there is a systemic conflict between profit and extent of care. Instead of controlling costs and maximizing profits, what if long-term care focused on our basic need to lead meaningful and connected lives until our deaths? What if staff members dropped the feigned hope of forestalling the inevitable and concentrated on making their charges comfortable and respected? These and other questions raised by this powerful book will cause Americans to rethink how nursing homes are run, staffed, and financed—as well as the circumstances under which we hope to meet our end.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/books/4</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1003&amp;amp;context=books&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>4</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>1003</articleid>
<submission-date>2005-09-19T11:33:38-07:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>Book Samples</publication-title>
<context-key>99741</context-key>
<submission-path>books/4</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="comments" type="string">
<value>The abstract, table of contents, and first twenty-five pages are published with permission from the Cornell University Press. For ordering information, please visit the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cornellpress.cornell.edu&quot; &gt;Cornell University Press&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;BR&gt;http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/books/4/</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2005-01-12T00:00:00-08:00</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>