<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>The Benefits and Costs of Employee Suggestions under Gainsharing</title>
<publication-date>2005-07-01T00:00:00-07:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<institution>Korea University, Seoul</institution>
<lname>Kim</lname>
<fname>Dong-One</fname>
</author>
</authors>
<keywords>
<keyword>employee suggestions</keyword>
<keyword>gainsharing</keyword>
<keyword>labor productivity</keyword>
<keyword>grievances</keyword>
<keyword>employee involvement programs</keyword>
<keyword>high-performance work practices</keyword>
</keywords>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Using data for the years 1985–92 from a discontinued suggestion program at a manufacturing plant in the United States, this study examines the benefits and costs of suggestions under gainsharing. The implemented suggestions are found to have improved labor productivity and reduced grievances and disciplinary actions, but more robust evidence suggests that they also incurred transaction costs and implementation costs. The author speculates that substantial transaction and implementation costs may be a factor responsible for the typically modest outcomes and generally short longevity of employee involvement programs and high-performance work practices.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/ilrreview/vol58/iss4/6</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1143&amp;amp;context=ilrreview&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>6</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>1143</articleid>
<submission-date>2005-07-13T11:26:03-07:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>ILR Review</publication-title>
<context-key>83235</context-key>
<submission-path>ilrreview/vol58/iss4/6</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="acknowledgements" type="string">
<value>The author thanks Steven E. Abraham, Paula B. Voos, Kenneth S. Mericle, Craig Olson, Richard U. Miller, Denis Collins, Roland Zullo, and W. Lee Hansen for their comments on various drafts of this paper.  An earlier version of this paper was presented at the 2000 Industrial Relations Research Association Meetings, Boston, January 7–9.  The analyses discussed in this paper were performed using the statistical package SPSS TRENDS.</value>
</field>
<field name="peer_reviewed" type="boolean">
<value>true</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2005-07-01T00:00:00-07:00</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>