<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>IWS Issue Brief - Where in the World Is Your Job Going?</title>
<publication-date>2005-09-01T00:00:00-07:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<email>me16@cornell.edu</email>
<institution>Institute of Workplace Studies</institution>
<lname>Edid</lname>
<fname>Maralyn</fname>
</author>
</authors>
<keywords>
<keyword>job</keyword>
<keyword>labor</keyword>
<keyword>worker</keyword>
<keyword>America</keyword>
<keyword>economic</keyword>
<keyword>trade</keyword>
<keyword>goods</keyword>
<keyword>services</keyword>
<keyword>skill</keyword>
<keyword>federal</keyword>
<keyword>government</keyword>
<keyword>offshoring</keyword>
<keyword>pay</keyword>
<keyword>export</keyword>
<keyword>foreign</keyword>
<keyword>wage</keyword>
</keywords>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s say you have a job processing credit card receipts, answering calls to a customer hotline, reading X-rays, or writing software code. Then one day the boss announces the facility is closing and you, along with all your co-workers, will be laid off. Shortly after, you learn from a news report in the local paper that workers in India are now performing the tasks that used to be handled in your office. In the article the company explained its decision to “offshore” jobs by noting the sizeable gap between the wages earned by its former employees in America and those earned by workers in that far away country.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/briefs/7</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1008&amp;amp;context=briefs&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>7</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>1008</articleid>
<submission-date>2005-09-15T08:02:25-07:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>Policy &amp; Issue Briefs</publication-title>
<context-key>99215</context-key>
<submission-path>briefs/7</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="comments" type="string">
<value>&lt;b&gt;Suggested Citation&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt; 
Edid, M. (2005). &lt;i&gt;Where in the World Is Your Job Going?&lt;/i&gt; (IWS Issue Briefs). Ithaca, NY: School of Industrial and Labor Relations, Cornell University.  http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/briefs/7/ 
&lt;P&gt;
The Issue Briefs, sponsored by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/iws/&quot; &gt;Institute for Workplace Studies&lt;/a href&gt;, provide a summary overview of the debate swirling around workplace-related current events. They are intended as a public service to inform readers about key issues and should not be construed as the opinion of IWS or the ILR School. These articles are based on extant sources, which are listed at the end of the text, and do not reflect original research by the author.</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2005-09-01T00:00:00-07:00</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>