<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>Vol. 1, sec. 6 (pp. 537-673). Continues with female workers’ testimony, Dec. 11-12, 1911. Adjourned to December 13</title>
<publication-date>1911-11-20T00:00:00-08:00</publication-date>
<authors>
</authors>
<keywords>
<keyword>triangle fire</keyword>
<keyword>rothstein</keyword>
<keyword>mayers</keyword>
<keyword>machine operator</keyword>
<keyword>zimmerman</keyword>
<keyword>weiner</keyword>
<keyword>lace cutter</keyword>
<keyword>employee</keyword>
<keyword>walker</keyword>
<keyword>examiner</keyword>
<keyword>weiner</keyword>
<keyword>axlerod</keyword>
<keyword>waist maker</keyword>
<keyword>bursky</keyword>
<keyword>operator</keyword>
<keyword>glantz</keyword>
</keywords>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Vol. 1, sec. 6 (pp. 537-673)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resumed December 12th, 1911. Testimony by female workers continues:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BECKIE ROTHSTEIN continues, describing actions of self and Sam Bernstein, who tried to open the door&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ROSE MAYERS, machine operator  (People’s witness, p. 549), testifies she tried to open door and others tried to help open it; prior conversations about the door with others&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SOPHIE ZIMMERMAN, machine operator (People’s witness, p. 564), assisted by interpreter, testified that she saw others try to open the door, unsuccessfully; notes she never saw the door open&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KATIE WEINER, employed as lace cutter (People’s witness, p. 576), testifies she tried to open door; asked about prior testimony at Coroner’s inquest; asked about who else she saw, injuries sustained at elevator&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CELIA WALKER, employed as examiner (People’s witness, p. 599), describes physical layout of work space on ninth floor; testifies she tried to open door; jumping over machines, jumping into elevator shaft, holding on to cable, going unconscious; questioned about orientation of flames and smoke; construction of door&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LILLIAN WEINER, employed as examiner (People’s witness, p. 635), describes physical layout of work space on ninth floor; testifies she tried to open door, and others before her tried and found it locked; testifies they were never allowed to open a window&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DORA AXLEROD, employed as a waist maker (People’s witness, p. 656), assisted by interpreter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BECKIE BURSKY, operator (People’s witness, p. 658), assisted by interpreter, discusses actions on day of fire, use of fire escape&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ROSE GLANTZ, operator (People’s witness, p. 664), discusses actions on day of fire, customary work routine, use of elevators&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adjourned to December 13, 1911&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/triangletrans/6</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1005&amp;amp;context=triangletrans&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>6</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>1005</articleid>
<submission-date>2005-08-24T10:48:26-07:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>Transcripts of Criminal Trial Against Triangle Owners</publication-title>
<context-key>88506</context-key>
<submission-path>triangletrans/6</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="comments" type="string">
<value>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/triangletrans/6</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>1911-11-20T00:00:00-08:00</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>