<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>Human Resource Management as a Substitute for Trade Unions in British Workplaces</title>
<publication-date>2005-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<institution>University College London</institution>
<lname>Machin</lname>
<fname>Stephen</fname>
</author>
<author>
<institution>University of Sheffield</institution>
<lname>Wood</lname>
<fname>Stephen</fname>
</author>
</authors>
<keywords>
<keyword>human resource management</keyword>
<keyword>HRM</keyword>
<keyword>trade unions</keyword>
<keyword>British workplaces</keyword>
<keyword>union decline</keyword>
<keyword>substitution effect</keyword>
</keywords>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;The authors use British workplace data for 1980–98 to examine whether increased human resource management (HRM) practices coincided with union decline, consistent with the hypothesis that such practices act as a substitute for unionization. Two initial analyses show no important differences between union and non-union sectors or between newer workplaces (which are likelier to be non-union) and older ones in the pattern of HRM practices over time; and the study’s longitudinal analysis picks up no evidence of faster union decline in workplaces or industries that adopted HRM practices than in those that did not. Not only is the hypothesized substitution effect thus not supported, but the authors even uncover some evidence of a complementarity between unions and HRM practices. The authors conclude that increased use of HRM practices is probably not an important factor underpinning union decline in Britain.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/ilrreview/vol58/iss2/2</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1122&amp;amp;context=ilrreview&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>2</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>1122</articleid>
<submission-date>2005-07-13T10:08:24-07:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>ILR Review</publication-title>
<context-key>83197</context-key>
<submission-path>ilrreview/vol58/iss2/2</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="acknowledgements" type="string">
<value>This research is part of a joint project between the Leverhulme Foundation–funded research on the Future of Trade Unionism in Modern Britain and the ESRC Centre for Innovation and Organisation (Grant Number RA013461).  The empirical research is based on data from the Workplace Industrial/Employee Relations series, which is deposited at the Data Archive at the University of Essex, U.K. (http://www.esrc.ac.uk).  The authors thank Alex Bryson, Peter Cappelli, and participants at the Labor seminar at Wharton Business School for comments, and Alison Geldart for editorial assistance.</value>
</field>
<field name="peer_reviewed" type="boolean">
<value>true</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2005-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>