<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>The Impact of Task-  and Team-Generic Teamwork Skills Training on Team Effectiveness</title>
<publication-date>2005-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<institution>The University of Arizona</institution>
<lname>Ellis</lname>
<fname>Aleksander</fname>
<mname>P. J.</mname>
</author>
<author>
<email>bb92@cornell.edu</email>
<institution>Cornell University</institution>
<lname>Bell</lname>
<fname>Bradford</fname>
<mname>S.</mname>
</author>
<author>
<institution>George Mason University</institution>
<lname>Ployhart</lname>
<fname>Robert</fname>
<mname>E.</mname>
</author>
<author>
<institution>Michigan State University</institution>
<lname>Hollenbeck</lname>
<fname>John</fname>
<mname>R.</mname>
</author>
<author>
<institution>Michigan State University</institution>
<lname>Ilgen</lname>
<fname>Daniel</fname>
<mname>R.</mname>
</author>
</authors>
<keywords>
<keyword>task</keyword>
<keyword>team-generic</keyword>
<keyword>teamwork</keyword>
<keyword>skills</keyword>
<keyword>training</keyword>
<keyword>team</keyword>
<keyword>members</keyword>
<keyword>effectiveness</keyword>
<keyword>coordination</keyword>
<keyword>collaborative problem solving</keyword>
<keyword>problem</keyword>
<keyword>communication</keyword>
<keyword>program</keyword>
<keyword>person</keyword>
<keyword>project</keyword>
<keyword>behavior</keyword>
</keywords>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;This study examined the effects of training team members in three task- and teamgeneric teamwork skills: planning and task coordination, collaborative problem solving, and communication. We first examined the degree to which task- and team-generic teamwork skills training impacted team performance on a task unrelated to the content of the training program.We then examined whether the effects of task- and team-generic teamwork skills training on team performance were due to the transfer of skills directly related to planning and task coordination, collaborative problem solving, and communication. Results from 65 four-person project teams indicated that task- and team-generic teamwork skills training led to significantly higher levels of team performance. Results also indicated that the effects of task- and teamgeneric teamwork skills training on team performance were mediated by planning and task coordination and collaborative problem solving behavior. Although communication was positively affected by the task- and team-generic teamwork skills training, it did not mediate the relationship between task- and team-generic teamwork skills training and team performance.Theoretical and practical implications of these results are discussed, as well as possible limitations and directions for future research.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cahrswp/1</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1000&amp;amp;context=cahrswp&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>1</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>1000</articleid>
<submission-date>2005-10-05T10:10:32-07:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>CAHRS Working Paper Series</publication-title>
<context-key>101693</context-key>
<submission-path>cahrswp/1</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="comments" type="string">
<value>&lt;B&gt;Suggested Citation&lt;/B&gt;&lt;BR&gt;Ellis, A. P. J., Bell, B. S., Ployhart, R. E., Hollenbeck, J. R.  &amp; Ilgen, D. R. (2005). &lt;I&gt; The impact of task- and team-generic teamwork skills training on team effectiveness &lt;/I&gt;(CAHRS Working Paper #05-01). Ithaca, NY: Cornell University, School of Industrial and Labor Relations, Center for Advanced Human Resource Studies. &lt;BR&gt;
http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cahrswp/1</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2005-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>