<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>Does Managed Care Change the Management of Nonprofit Hospitals?  Evidence from the Executive Labor Market</title>
<publication-date>2005-04-01T00:00:00-08:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<institution>University of Chicago</institution>
<lname>Bertrand</lname>
<fname>Marianne</fname>
</author>
<author>
<institution>University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign</institution>
<lname>Hallock</lname>
<fname>Kevin</fname>
<mname>F</mname>
</author>
<author>
<institution>University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign</institution>
<lname>Arnould</lname>
<fname>Richard</fname>
</author>
</authors>
<keywords>
<keyword>managed care</keyword>
<keyword>nonprofit hospitals</keyword>
<keyword>executive labor market</keyword>
<keyword>HMOs</keyword>
<keyword>executive turnover</keyword>
<keyword>executive pay</keyword>
</keywords>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;This paper examines how the managerial labor market in nonprofit hospitals has adjusted to the financial pressures induced by HMO penetration. Using a panel of about 1,500 nonprofit hospitals over the period 1992–96, the authors find that top executive turnover increased following an increase in HMO penetration. Moreover, the increase in turnover was concentrated among the hospitals that had lower levels of economic profitability. While the link between top executive pay and for-profit performance measures was on average very weak, HMO penetration tightened that link: as HMO penetration increased, top executives were compensated more for improving the profitability of their hospitals. These results, while of limited economic magnitude, are qualitatively consistent with the view that HMO penetration has increased the weight assigned to for-profit performance in the management of not-for-profit hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/ilrreview/vol58/iss3/10</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1137&amp;amp;context=ilrreview&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>10</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>1137</articleid>
<submission-date>2005-07-13T11:00:25-07:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>ILR Review</publication-title>
<context-key>83223</context-key>
<submission-path>ilrreview/vol58/iss3/10</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="acknowledgements" type="string">
<value>The authors are very grateful to seminar participants at the University of California at Berkeley, the University of Illinois, Princeton University, Texas A&amp;M University, the AEA Meetings, and the NBER Conference on the Industrial Organization of Healthcare, as well as to Orley Ashenfelter, David Card, Janet Currie, Larry DeBrock, Mark Killingsworth, David Lee, Jonathan Leonard, Darren Lubotsky, Sendhil Mullanaithan, Ronald Oaxaca, Michael Ransom, Clayton Reck, Kathryn Shaw, and Finis Welch for many helpful comments.  They also thank Sara Christopher and Srikanth Kadyala for excellent research assistance.  This research was supported by the Institute of Labor and Industrial Relations and the College of Business at the University of Illinois, and by a grant from the National Bureau of Economic Research.</value>
</field>
<field name="peer_reviewed" type="boolean">
<value>true</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2005-04-01T00:00:00-08:00</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>