<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>Assisting the Transition from Workfare to Work:  A Randomized Experiment</title>
<publication-date>2004-10-01T00:00:00-07:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<institution>North Carolina State University</institution>
<lname>Allen</lname>
<fname>Steven</fname>
<mname>G</mname>
</author>
<author>
<institution>North Carolina State University</institution>
<lname>Clark</lname>
<fname>Robert</fname>
<mname>L</mname>
</author>
<author>
<institution>Eastern Illinois University</institution>
<lname>Ghent</lname>
<fname>Linda</fname>
<mname>S</mname>
</author>
</authors>
<keywords>
<keyword>workfare</keyword>
<keyword>Argentina</keyword>
<keyword>Proempleo Experiment</keyword>
<keyword>wage subsidies</keyword>
<keyword>welfare</keyword>
<keyword>vouchers</keyword>
<keyword>skill training</keyword>
<keyword>training programs</keyword>
<keyword>randomization</keyword>
</keywords>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;To help workers navigate the transition from work to retirement more effectively, employers have been launching phased retirement programs, which allow older employees to work part-time and receive full retirement benefits. This paper examines the experience of the phased retirement system for tenured faculty in the University of North Carolina system over the years 1996– 98. After phased retirement was introduced, there was a sizable increase in the overall separation rate in the system. The key finding from an empirical analysis of the retirement decision as a function of pension incentives, employee performance, demographics, and campus characteristics is that the odds of entering phased retirement were strongly and inversely related to employee performance, as measured by recent pay increases.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/ilrreview/vol58/iss1/6</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1120&amp;amp;context=ilrreview&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>6</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>1120</articleid>
<submission-date>2005-07-13T09:44:12-07:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>ILR Review</publication-title>
<context-key>83192</context-key>
<submission-path>ilrreview/vol58/iss1/6</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="acknowledgements" type="string">
<value>The work reported in this paper is part of the ex-post evaluation of the World Bank’s Social Protection III Project in Argentina.  The authors thank the staff of the Trabajar project office in the Ministry of Labor, Government of Argentina, who helped in countless ways, and the Bank’s Manager for the project, Polly Jones, for her continuing support of the evaluation effort.  They also thank Julio Zelarayan, who managed the operations of the experiment and the data processing.  For comments, the authors are grateful to Robert Boruch, Polly Jones, Michael Lokshin, Biju Rao, Dominique van de Walle, and participants at presentations given at the Ministry of Labor Argentina, the Latin American and Caribbean Economics Association, the World Bank, and Yale University.  These are the views of the authors, and need not reflect those of the Government of Argentina or the World Bank.</value>
</field>
<field name="peer_reviewed" type="boolean">
<value>true</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2004-10-01T00:00:00-07:00</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>