<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>Tight Labor Markets and the Demand for Education:  Evidence from the Coal Boom and Bust</title>
<publication-date>2005-10-01T00:00:00-07:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<institution>Syracuse University</institution>
<lname>Black</lname>
<fname>Dan</fname>
<mname>A</mname>
</author>
<author>
<institution>University of Colorado</institution>
<lname>McKinnish</lname>
<fname>Terra</fname>
<mname>G</mname>
</author>
<author>
<institution>University of Maryland</institution>
<lname>Sanders</lname>
<fname>Seth</fname>
<mname>G.</mname>
</author>
</authors>
<subject-areas>
<subject-area>Subject area picklist required for setup.</subject-area>
</subject-areas>
<keywords>
<keyword>labor markets and school enrollment</keyword>
<keyword>tight labor markets and education</keyword>
</keywords>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Human capital theory predicts that individuals acquire less schooling when the returns to schooling are small. To test this theory, the authors study the effect of the Appalachian coal boom on high school enrollments. During the 1970s, a boom in the coal industry increased the earnings of high school dropouts relative to those of graduates. During the 1980s, the boom subsided and the earnings of dropouts declined relative to those of graduates. The authors find that high school enrollment rates in Kentucky and Pennsylvania declined considerably in the 1970s and increased in the 1980s in coal-producing counties relative to counties without coal. The estimates indicate that a longterm 10% increase in the earnings of low-skilled workers could decrease high school enrollment rates by as much as 5–7%—a finding with implications for policies aimed at improving low-skilled workers’ employment and earnings, such as wage subsidies and minimum wage increases.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/ilrreview/vol59/iss1/1</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1178&amp;amp;context=ilrreview&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>1</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>1178</articleid>
<submission-date>2005-09-23T12:14:16-07:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>ILR Review</publication-title>
<context-key>100376</context-key>
<submission-path>ilrreview/vol59/iss1/1</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="acknowledgements" type="string">
<value>The authors thank Steve Allen, Susan Black, Leigh
Ann Leshock, Philip McGivney, Sameer Makada, Hoda
Makar, Victoria Moyer, Reginald Roberts, and George
Tita for their research assistance. Seth Sanders received
support in the form of a Research Initiation
Grant from Carnegie Mellon University. Black acknowledges
research support from the Heinz School
of Public Policy and Management at Carnegie Mellon
University. The authors also gratefully acknowledge
financial support from the National Science Foundation.</value>
</field>
<field name="peer_reviewed" type="boolean">
<value>true</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2005-10-01T00:00:00-07:00</value>
</field>
<field name="short_title" type="string">
<value>Tight Labor Markets and the Demand for Education</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>