<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>Vol. 3, sec. 6 (pp. 1663-1802). Testimony by William Greenspan, former employee; testimony by workers: sewing machine operators, stenographer, pocket-book inspector, shipping supervisor, foreladies, stock supervisor, button marker, buttonhole maker</title>
<publication-date>1911-12-20T00:00:00-08:00</publication-date>
<authors>
</authors>
<keywords>
<keyword>triangle fire</keyword>
<keyword>greenspan</keyword>
<keyword>kestenbau</keyword>
<keyword>employee</keyword>
<keyword>court clerk</keyword>
<keyword>rosenfeld</keyword>
<keyword>operator</keyword>
<keyword>salub</keyword>
<keyword>night watchman</keyword>
<keyword>pasterneck</keyword>
<keyword>machine operator</keyword>
<keyword>kaplan</keyword>
<keyword>forelady</keyword>
<keyword>operator</keyword>
<keyword>alter</keyword>
<keyword>stenographer</keyword>
<keyword>alter</keyword>
<keyword>markowitz</keyword>
<keyword>shipping</keyword>
<keyword>tiger</keyword>
<keyword>operator</keyword>
<keyword>elbaum</keyword>
<keyword>forelady</keyword>
<keyword>wortman</keyword>
<keyword>stock</keyword>
<keyword>okan</keyword>
<keyword>button marker</keyword>
<keyword>iacovella</keyword>
<keyword>buttonhole maker</keyword>
</keywords>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Vol. 3, sec. 6 (pp. 1663-1802)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WILLIAM GREENSPAN, employee (defendants’ witness, p. 1663), received raise after fire, no longer employed by Harris &amp; Blanck; describes actions of self and others on day of fire; questioned at great length about previous testimony&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HARRY KESTENBAUM, court clerk (People’s witness, p. 1695), questioned about witnesses at the Coroner’s inquest&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WILLIAM GREENSPAN resumes the stand, asked to identify James Sheridan; does not recognize him&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ROSE ROSENFELD, operator (defendants’ witness, p. 1704), describes actions on day of fire&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NATHAN SALUB, night watchman (defendants’ witness, p. 1707), assisted by interpreter, testifies that he routinely locked all the doors; unlocked all of them the day of the fire; describes how he escaped; describes string on key; questioned about previous testimony&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adjourned, resumed December 22, 1911&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SALUB continues&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FRANK PASTERNECK, machine operator (defendants’ witness, p 1723), assisted by interpreter, describes layout of premises, actions on day of fire&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EVA KAPLAN, forelady/operator (defendants’ witness, p 1731), testifies Washington Place door was always open in summer, closed in winter; describes routine way she and others left building&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MARY ALTER, stenographer for Harris &amp; Blanck, related to both (defendants’ witness, p 1737), describes messages sent on switchboard and other devices between floors on day of fire, appearance of reflection of flames&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LOUIS ALTER, inspected bags of female workers as they left each day, (defendants’ witness, p 1750), described process; related to Harris &amp; Blanck&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EDWARD N. MARKOWITZ, in charge of shipping department (defendants’ witness, p 1755), describes attempts to evacuated others; appearance of flames&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DORA TIGER, operator (defendants’ witness, p 1768), describes routine way of passing between floors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THERESA ELBAUM, forelady (defendants’ witness, p 1786), describes routine way of passing between floors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PETER WORTMAN, in charge of stock department (embroideries and laces) (defendants’ witness, p 1789), had girlfriend on another floor; describes routine way of passing between floors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IDA OKAN, button marker (defendants’ witness, p 1792), describes routine way she and others passed between floors; notes Washington Place door was open in summer, closed in winter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MICHAEL IACOVELLA, buttonhole maker (defendants’ witness, p 1799), describes routine way of passing between floors; notes employees were able to dance during strike when phonograph was provided; noted seeing Blanck try the door several times&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/triangletrans/12</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1011&amp;amp;context=triangletrans&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>12</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>1011</articleid>
<submission-date>2005-08-24T11:48:26-07:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>Transcripts of Criminal Trial Against Triangle Owners</publication-title>
<context-key>88527</context-key>
<submission-path>triangletrans/12</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="comments" type="string">
<value>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/triangletrans/12</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>1911-12-20T00:00:00-08:00</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>