<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>Employment Determination in Enterprises under Communism and in Transition:  Evidence from Central Europe</title>
<publication-date>2005-04-01T00:00:00-08:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<institution>McGill University</institution>
<lname>Basu</lname>
<fname>Swati</fname>
</author>
<author>
<institution>London Business School</institution>
<lname>Estrin</lname>
<fname>Saul</fname>
</author>
<author>
<institution>University of Michigan</institution>
<lname>Svejnar</lname>
<fname>Jan</fname>
</author>
</authors>
<keywords>
<keyword>employment determination</keyword>
<keyword>communism</keyword>
<keyword>transition from communism to capitalism</keyword>
<keyword>central Europe</keyword>
<keyword>transition economies</keyword>
<keyword>central planning</keyword>
<keyword>Czech Republic</keyword>
<keyword>Hungary</keyword>
<keyword>Poland</keyword>
<keyword>Slovakia</keyword>
<keyword>labor hoarding</keyword>
</keywords>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;The authors present a comparative analysis of employment determination in four transition economies as they moved from central planning to a market economy in the early 1990s. They use firm-level panel data sets from the Czech Republic, Hungary, Poland, and Slovakia to estimate dynamic employment equations for the period from immediately before to immediately after the start of transition. For the most part, firms appear to have been quick to adjust employment to wage levels, and there is little evidence of labor hoarding. There were important cross-country variations in the determinants of employment during the reform process, however. Hungarian and Polish firms started the transition already substantially reformed, and became even more responsive to market signals as transition proceeded. In contrast, firms in the Czech and Slovak Republics started in the completely unresponsive mode characteristic of central planning, but rapidly caught up with their counterparts in Hungary and Poland.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/ilrreview/vol58/iss3/3</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1130&amp;amp;context=ilrreview&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>3</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>1130</articleid>
<submission-date>2005-07-13T10:38:54-07:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>ILR Review</publication-title>
<context-key>83210</context-key>
<submission-path>ilrreview/vol58/iss3/3</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="acknowledgements" type="string">
<value>In undertaking the research for this paper, Saul Estrin and Jan Svejnar were in part supported by World Bank research grants for research on Enterprises in Transition and Labor Markets in Transition, respectively, and by ACE PHARE grant No. P96–6095-R.  Svejnar in part also benefited from NSF grant No. SES–0111783.  The authors would like to thank Olivier Blanchard, Tito Boeri, Simon Commander, George Johnson, and participants in seminars at Princeton University, the London Business School, the University of Pittsburgh, and the Davidson Institute Annual Workshop on Transition Economics for valuable comments.  They are also indebted to Lubomir Lizal, Miroslav Singer, Lina Takla, and Chris Walters for valuable computer assistance.</value>
</field>
<field name="peer_reviewed" type="boolean">
<value>true</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2005-04-01T00:00:00-08:00</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>