<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>Unwelcome And Unlawful: Sexual Harassment in the American Workplace</title>
<publication-date>2005-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<lname>Gregory</lname>
<fname>Raymond</fname>
<mname>F.</mname>
</author>
</authors>
<keywords>
<keyword>sexual harassment</keyword>
<keyword>women</keyword>
<keyword>workplace</keyword>
<keyword>legal</keyword>
<keyword>law</keyword>
<keyword>conduct</keyword>
<keyword>right</keyword>
<keyword>employer</keyword>
<keyword>men</keyword>
<keyword>power</keyword>
<keyword>sex</keyword>
<keyword>unlawful</keyword>
<keyword>court</keyword>
</keywords>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Nearly every American woman will, at some point during her working life, be sexually harassed, according to Raymond F. Gregory, a lawyer specializing in employment and discrimination law. This book provides information for those victims as well as for those suffering same sex harassment and for male victims of sexual harassment. Gregory analyzes sexual harassment from the perspective of existing federal law and describes the legal rights that may be asserted by victims of harassment to obtain either injunctive or monetary relief. By clarifying little understood aspects of the law barring sexual harassment, the author presents an indispensable resource for victims seeking to learn what to expect from the legal system if they contest the actions of their harassers in the courts.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/books/6</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1005&amp;amp;context=books&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>6</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>1005</articleid>
<submission-date>2005-09-20T05:57:11-07:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>Book Samples</publication-title>
<context-key>99861</context-key>
<submission-path>books/6</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="comments" type="string">
<value>The abstract, table of contents, and first twenty-five pages are published with permission from the Cornell University Press. For ordering information, please visit the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cornellpress.cornell.edu&quot; &gt;Cornell University Press&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;BR&gt;http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/books/6/</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2005-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>