<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>Did American Welfare Capitalists Breach Their Implicit Contracts During the Great Depression?  Preliminary Findings from Company-Level Data</title>
<publication-date>2005-10-01T00:00:00-07:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<institution>Northwestern University</institution>
<lname>Moriguchi</lname>
<fname>Chiaki</fname>
</author>
</authors>
<keywords>
<keyword>Welfare Capitalists</keyword>
<keyword>Great Depression</keyword>
<keyword>implicit contracts</keyword>
</keywords>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;It has been claimed that American employers’ experiments in private welfare capitalism collapsed during the Great Depression, giving place to the welfare state and industrial unionism. Recent studies, however, reveal considerable differences in experience across firms. The author of this study, who characterizes private welfare capitalism as a set of human resource management practices constituting an implicit contract equilibrium, tests the implications of implicit contract theory using data from fourteen leading manufacturing firms. The repudiation of implicit contracts, she finds, was positively correlated with the severity of the depression’s impact experienced by firms and negatively correlated with the effectiveness of “internal enforcement mechanisms” instituted by firms. Furthermore, she finds that greater breaches of implicit contracts were associated with greater employee support for industrial unions and more explicit employment contracts concluded under the New Deal. A comparative case study complements the quantitative analysis by exploring internal dynamics.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/ilrreview/vol59/iss1/4</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1181&amp;amp;context=ilrreview&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>4</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>1181</articleid>
<submission-date>2005-09-23T12:34:16-07:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>ILR Review</publication-title>
<context-key>100381</context-key>
<submission-path>ilrreview/vol59/iss1/4</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="acknowledgements" type="string">
<value>The author thanks Megan
MacGarvie, Erika McCaffrey, and Hilah Geer for their
research assistance. For valuable comments, she also
thanks Ran Abramitzky, Lee Alston, Louis Cain, Joseph
Ferrie, Price Fishback, Robert Gibbons, Avner
Greif, Roger Horowitz, Luojia Hu, Sanford Jacoby,
Zorina Khan, Joel Mokyr, Robert Porter, Peter Temin,
Eric Van den Steen, and seminar participants at the
NBER, Northwestern University, Stanford University,
U.C. Berkeley, the University of Michigan, the University
of Toronto, and MIT. Finally, she gratefully
acknowledges financial support received from the
Harvard Business School Division of Research when
she was a faculty member.</value>
</field>
<field name="peer_reviewed" type="boolean">
<value>true</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2005-10-01T00:00:00-07:00</value>
</field>
<field name="short_title" type="string">
<value>Welfare Capitalists During the Great Depression</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>