<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>Minimum Wages, Labor Market Institutions, and Youth Employment:  A Cross-National Analysis</title>
<publication-date>2004-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<institution>Michigan State University</institution>
<lname>Neumark</lname>
<fname>David</fname>
</author>
<author>
<institution>Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System</institution>
<lname>Wascher</lname>
<fname>William</fname>
</author>
</authors>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;The authors estimate the employment effects of changes in national minimum wages using a pooled cross-section time-series data set comprising 17 OECD countries for the period 1975–2000. The average effects they find are consistent with the view that minimum wages cause employment losses among youths. However, the evidence also shows considerable variation across countries. In particular, disemployment effects of minimum wages appear to be smaller in countries that have subminimum wage provisions for youths. Regarding other labor market policies and institutions, the authors find that more restrictive labor standards and higher union coverage strengthen the disemployment effects of minimum wages, while employment protection laws and active labor market policies designed to bring unemployed individuals into the work force help to offset these effects. Overall, the disemployment effects of minimum wages are strongest in the countries with the least regulated labor markets.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/ilrreview/vol57/iss2/4</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1058&amp;amp;context=ilrreview&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>4</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>1058</articleid>
<submission-date>2005-07-11T12:05:57-07:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>ILR Review</publication-title>
<context-key>82911</context-key>
<submission-path>ilrreview/vol57/iss2/4</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="acknowledgements" type="string">
<value>The initial work on this paper was done while Wascher was a visiting economist at the Bank for International Settlements.  The authors are grateful to Norman Bowers, Daniel Hansen, Mark Keese, Stephen Machin, and Alan Manning for help in obtaining the data, and to Palle Andersen, Linda Bell, and Daniel Hamermesh for helpful comments.  The views expressed are those of the authors only, and do not necessarily reflect those of the Federal Reserve Board, the Bank for International Settlements, or the Public Policy Institute of California.</value>
</field>
<field name="peer_reviewed" type="boolean">
<value>true</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2004-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>