<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>Skilled Hands, Strong Spirits: A Century of Building Trades History</title>
<publication-date>2005-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<lname>Palladino</lname>
<fname>Grace</fname>
</author>
</authors>
<keywords>
<keyword>trade</keyword>
<keyword>union</keyword>
<keyword>building</keyword>
<keyword>work</keyword>
<keyword>jurisdiction</keyword>
<keyword>labor</keyword>
<keyword>skill</keyword>
<keyword>skyscrapers</keyword>
<keyword>business</keyword>
<keyword>wage</keyword>
<keyword>council</keyword>
<keyword>strike</keyword>
<keyword>carpenter</keyword>
</keywords>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Skilled Hands, Strong Spirits follows the history of the AFL-CIO Building and Construction Trades Department from the emergence of building trades councils in the age of the skyscraper; through treacherous fights over jurisdiction as new building materials and methods of work evolved; and through numerous Department campaigns to improve safety standards, work with contractors to promote unionized construction, and forge a sense of industrial unity among its fifteen (and at times nineteen) autonomous and highly diverse affiliates. Arranged chronologically, Skilled Hands, Strong Spirits is based on archival research in Department, AFL-CIO, and U.S. government records as well as numerous union journals, the local and national press, and interviews with former Department officers.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/books/13</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1012&amp;amp;context=books&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>13</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>1012</articleid>
<submission-date>2005-09-21T06:16:03-07:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>Book Samples</publication-title>
<context-key>100022</context-key>
<submission-path>books/13</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="comments" type="string">
<value>The abstract, table of contents, and first twenty-five pages are published with permission from the Cornell University Press. For ordering information, please visit the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cornellpress.cornell.edu&quot; &gt;Cornell University Press&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;BR&gt;
http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/books/13/</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2005-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>