<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>Global Talentship: Toward a Decision Science Connecting Talent to Global  Strategic Success</title>
<publication-date>2002-09-15T00:00:00-07:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<institution>Cornell University</institution>
<lname>Boudreau</lname>
<fname>John</fname>
<mname>W.</mname>
</author>
<author>
<institution>Personnel Decisions International</institution>
<lname>Ramstad</lname>
<fname>Peter</fname>
<mname>M.</mname>
</author>
<author>
<institution>University of Canberra</institution>
<lname>Dowling</lname>
<fname>Peter</fname>
<mname>J.</mname>
</author>
</authors>
<keywords>
<keyword>work</keyword>
<keyword>development</keyword>
<keyword>success</keyword>
<keyword>leader</keyword>
<keyword>research</keyword>
<keyword>HRM</keyword>
<keyword>job</keyword>
<keyword>organization</keyword>
<keyword>managers</keyword>
<keyword>employees</keyword>
</keywords>
<disciplines><discipline>Human Resources Management</discipline>
</disciplines><abstract>&lt;p&gt;It is widely accepted that global competitive advantage frequently requires managing such complex situations that traditional organization and job structures are simply insufficient. Increasingly, in order to create a flexible and integrated set of decisions that balance local flexibility with global efficiency, organizations must rely on more social, informal and matrix-based shared visions among managers and employees. Research on global strategic advantage, global organizational structures, and even shared mindsets has suggested that dimensions of culture, product and function provide a valuable organizing framework. However, typical decisions about organization structure, HRM practices and talent often remain framed at such a high level as to preclude their solution. We maintain that there is often no logical answer to such questions as, “Should the sales force be local or global?” or “Should product authority rest with the countries or the corporate center?” However, we propose that embedding business processes or value chains within a Culture and Product matrix provides the necessary analytic detail to reveal otherwise elusive solutions. Moreover, by linking this global process matrix to a model that bridges strategy and talent, it is possible to identify global “pivotal talent pools,” and to target organizational and human resource investments toward those talent areas that have the greatest impact on strategic advantage. We demonstrate the Value-Chain, Culture and Product (VCCP) matrix using several examples, and discuss future research and practical implications, particularly for leadership and leadership development.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cahrswp/62</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1061&amp;amp;context=cahrswp&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>62</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>1061</articleid>
<submission-date>2005-10-26T08:49:36-07:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>CAHRS Working Paper Series</publication-title>
<context-key>112571</context-key>
<submission-path>cahrswp/62</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="comments" type="string">
<value>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Suggested Citation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Boudreau, J. W., Ramstad, P. M. &amp; Dowling, P. J. (2002). &lt;em&gt; Global talentship: Toward a decision science connecting talent to global strategic success &lt;/em&gt; (CAHRS Working Paper #02-21). Ithaca, NY: Cornell University, School of Industrial and Labor Relations, Center for Advanced Human Resource Studies. &lt;br /&gt;http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cahrswp/62&lt;/p&gt;</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2002-09-15T00:00:00-07:00</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>