<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>The Effect of Registered Nurses&#39; Unions on Heart-Attack Mortality</title>
<publication-date>2004-04-01T00:00:00-08:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<institution>University of Massachusetts, Amherst</institution>
<lname>Ash</lname>
<fname>Michael</fname>
</author>
<author>
<institution>University of California, San Francisco</institution>
<lname>Seago</lname>
<fname>Jean</fname>
<mname>Ann</mname>
</author>
</authors>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Although hospital work organization affects patient outcomes and in some states registered nurses (R.N.’s) are increasingly forming unions, the relationship between R.N. unions and patient outcomes has received little attention. This study examines the relationship between R.N. unionization and the mortality rate for acute myocardial infarction (AMI), or heart attack, in acute-care hospitals in California. After controlling for patient and hospital characteristics, the authors find that hospitals with unionized R.N.’s have 5.5% lower heartattack mortality than do non-union hospitals. This result remains substantively unchanged when the analysis accounts for possible selection bias—specifically, the possibility that unionized hospitals have certain important but unobservable characteristics, independent of unionization, that affect patient care.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/ilrreview/vol57/iss3/6</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1077&amp;amp;context=ilrreview&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>6</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>1077</articleid>
<submission-date>2005-07-12T07:19:51-07:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>ILR Review</publication-title>
<context-key>83000</context-key>
<submission-path>ilrreview/vol57/iss3/6</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="acknowledgements" type="string">
<value>For financial support, the authors are grateful for the 1998 American Nurses Foundation grant, UCSF, the Center for the Health Professions (Edward O&#39;Neil and Jonathan Showstack, Directors), and the UCSF Center for California Health Workforce Studies (Kevin Grumbach, Director).  For data, they thank Harold S. Luft and Patrick Romano from the California Hospital Outcomes Project (CHOP), sponsored by the California Office of Statewide Health Planning and Development (OSHPD).  For editorial comments, they thank George Akerlof, University of California, Berkeley; Lee Badgett, University of Massachusetts, Amherst; and Joanne Spetz, Research Fellow, Public Policy Institute of California and Assistant Adjunct Professor, University of California, San Francisco.  For research assistance, they thank Radoslaw Macik and the Department of Economics at the University of Massachusetts, Amherst, and David Biondi-Sexton and the Department of Community Health Systems at UCSF.</value>
</field>
<field name="peer_reviewed" type="boolean">
<value>true</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2004-04-01T00:00:00-08:00</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>