<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>Mutual Gains or Zero Sum?  Labor Relations and Firm Performance in the Airline Industry</title>
<publication-date>2004-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<institution>Brandeis University</institution>
<lname>Gittell</lname>
<fname>Jody</fname>
<mname>Hoffer</mname>
</author>
<author>
<institution>Massachusetts Institute of Technology</institution>
<lname>Nordenflycht</lname>
<fname>Andrew</fname>
<mname>von</mname>
</author>
<author>
<institution>Massachusetts Institute of Technology</institution>
<lname>Kochan</lname>
<fname>Thomas</fname>
<mname>A</mname>
</author>
</authors>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;The authors examine competing theoretical arguments regarding whether union representation, shared governance, wage levels, and two features of the quality of labor relations—workplace culture and conflict in negotiations—lead to better or worse outcomes for airlines, and they test these interpretations using a mix of historical and quantitative data from major U.S. airlines. Both the qualitative and quantitative results suggest that relational factors—conflict and workplace culture—are more important determinants of performance than the structural factors of unionization, shared governance, and wages. The authors conclude that efforts to recover from the current crisis in the airline industry that depend primarily on reductions in wages or union power will at best bring only short-term relief from immediate financial pressures. Sustained improvement in service quality and financial performance will require more fundamental improvements in the quality of labor relations.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/ilrreview/vol57/iss2/1</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1055&amp;amp;context=ilrreview&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>1</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>1055</articleid>
<submission-date>2005-07-11T11:55:25-07:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>ILR Review</publication-title>
<context-key>82908</context-key>
<submission-path>ilrreview/vol57/iss2/1</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="acknowledgements" type="string">
<value>The authors are grateful to their colleagues Robert McKersie and Peter Belobaba and to other members of the MIT Global Airline Industry Program and its Advisory Board for their input into this paper.  They are also grateful to Norman Strickman of the U.S. Department of Transportation and Rob DeLucia of the Airline Industrial Relations Conference for generously supplying archival data.  Thanks also to participants in the Institute of Work and Employment Relations at MIT and to participants in the 2001 Industrial Relations Research Association meetings in New Orleans for their valuable comments.  This study was conducted as part of the MIT Global Airline Industry Program and was funded by the Alfred P. Sloan Foundation and the Harvard Business School Division of Research.</value>
</field>
<field name="peer_reviewed" type="boolean">
<value>true</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2004-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>