<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>Vol. 3, sec. 7 (pp. 1803-1901). Testimony by workers; and by Isaac Harris, co-defendant/owner, who describes earlier fires, petty thefts by workers, inspection of pocket-books, layout of premises</title>
<publication-date>1911-12-20T00:00:00-08:00</publication-date>
<authors>
</authors>
<keywords>
<keyword>triangle fire</keyword>
<keyword>cohen</keyword>
<keyword>lipschitz</keyword>
<keyword>teschner</keyword>
<keyword>harris</keyword>
<keyword>machine operator</keyword>
<keyword>time keeper</keyword>
<keyword>salesman</keyword>
<keyword>telautography</keyword>
<keyword>sister</keyword>
<keyword>sleeve maker</keyword>
<keyword>oranstein</keyword>
<keyword>puser</keyword>
<keyword>carpenter</keyword>
<keyword>bernstein</keyword>
<keyword>machine operator</keyword>
<keyword>harris</keyword>
<keyword>owner</keyword>
<keyword>employee</keyword>
</keywords>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Vol. 3, sec. 7 (pp. 1803-1901)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ROSE COHEN, machine operator (defendants’ witness, p 1803), through interpreter, describes going through the Washington Place door, seeing others go through it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DINAH LIPSCHITZ, time keeper, operated telautograph (intercom/telephone device) (defendants’ witness, p 1805), still employed by firm, related to Harris &amp; Blanck; says door was never locked; questioned about previous testimony about whether the door was kept open&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EMILE W. TESCHNER, salesman employed by Harris &amp; Blanck (defendants’ witness, p 1816), says he never had to use a key to get in or out of the Washington Place stairway door&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EVA HARRIS, Harris’s sister (defendants’ witness, p 1821), worked at machine, described what happened day of the fire&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SAM ORANSTEIN, sleeve maker (defendants’ witness, p 1824), assisted by interpreter, says he saw people coming in and out of the Washington Place door&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DAVE PUSER, carpenter (defendants’ witness, p 1827), assisted by interpreter, describes partition he built&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ABRAHAM BERNSTEIN, machine operator (defendants’ witness, p 1839), assisted by interpreter, testifies about the Washington Place door; questioned about previous testimony&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ISAAC HARRIS, one of the defendants, testifies on his own behalf, p. 1846, describes hours he kept, how he spent his time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ABRAHAM BERNSTEIN resumes stand, p. 1848, asked to identify interpreter of his testimony at District Attorney’s office, Joseph Pell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ISAAC HARRIS resumes stand, p. 1849, describes how he went from floor to floor, testifies that he never carried a key, describes actions on the day of the fire; questioned about earlier fires in the building, less than $25 worth of thefts by employees, reason for inspecting pocket books; questioned about age of operators; describes physical layout, location of bins of cuttings&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/triangletrans/13</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1012&amp;amp;context=triangletrans&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>13</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>1012</articleid>
<submission-date>2005-08-24T11:50:20-07:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>Transcripts of Criminal Trial Against Triangle Owners</publication-title>
<context-key>88528</context-key>
<submission-path>triangletrans/13</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="comments" type="string">
<value>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/triangletrans/13</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>1911-12-20T00:00:00-08:00</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>