<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>Goal Orientation and Ability:  Interactive Effects on Self-Efficacy, Performance, and Knowledge</title>
<publication-date>2002-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<email>bb92@cornell.edu</email>
<institution>Cornell University</institution>
<lname>Bell</lname>
<fname>Bradford</fname>
<mname>S.</mname>
</author>
<author>
<institution>Michigan State University</institution>
<lname>Kozlowski</lname>
<fname>Steve</fname>
<mname>W.J.</mname>
</author>
</authors>
<keywords>
<keyword>Goal</keyword>
<keyword>orientation</keyword>
<keyword>ability</keyword>
<keyword>cognition</keyword>
<keyword>performance</keyword>
<keyword>learning</keyword>
<keyword>self-efficacy</keyword>
<keyword>knowledge</keyword>
<keyword>individual</keyword>
</keywords>
<disciplines><discipline>Human Resources Management</discipline>
</disciplines><abstract>&lt;p&gt;This study examined the direct relationship of goal orientation – and the interaction of goal orientation and cognitive ability -- with self-efficacy, performance, and knowledge in a learning context. The current paper argues that whether a particular type of goal orientation is adaptive or not adaptive depends on individuals&#39; cognitive ability. Results indicated that the direct associations of learning and performance orientations were consistent with previous research. Learning orientation was positively related to self-efficacy, performance, and knowledge, while performance orientation was negatively related to only one outcome, performance. The interactions between goal orientation and ability also supported several hypotheses. As expected, learning orientation was generally adaptive for high ability individuals, but had no effect for low ability individuals. In contrast, the effects of performance orientation were contingent on both individuals&#39; level of cognitive ability and the outcome examined. The implications of these results for future research on goal orientation are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/hrpubs/9</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1008&amp;amp;context=hrpubs&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>9</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>1008</articleid>
<submission-date>2005-06-21T08:07:46-07:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>Faculty Publications - Human Resource Studies</publication-title>
<context-key>81170</context-key>
<submission-path>hrpubs/9</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="comments" type="string">
<value>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Suggested Citation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Bell, B. S., &amp; Kozlowski, S. W. J. (2002). Goal orientation and ability: Interactive effects on self-efficacy, performance, and knowledge. Retrieved [insert date], from Cornell University, School of Industrial and Labor Relations site:&lt;br /&gt;http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/hrpubs/9/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Required Publisher Statement&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt; This article may not exactly replicate the final version published in the APA journal. It is not the copy of record. Final paper published as Bell, B. S., &amp; Kozlowski, S. W. J. (2002). Goal orientation and ability: Interactive effects on self-efficacy, performance, and knowledge. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apa.org/journals/apl/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Journal of Applied Psychology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;87&lt;/em&gt;, 497-505.&lt;/p&gt;</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2002-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>