<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>Unions, Work-Related Training, and Wages:  Evidence for British Men</title>
<publication-date>2003-10-01T00:00:00-07:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<institution>University of Essex</institution>
<lname>Booth</lname>
<fname>Alison</fname>
<mname>L</mname>
</author>
<author>
<institution>University of Essex</institution>
<lname>Francesconi</lname>
<fname>Marco</fname>
</author>
<author>
<institution>University of London</institution>
<lname>Zoega</lname>
<fname>Gylfi</fname>
</author>
</authors>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Using data for the years 1991–96 from the British Household Panel Survey, the authors investigate how union coverage affected work-related training and how the union-training link affected wages and wage growth for a sample of fulltime men. Relative to non-covered workers, union-covered workers were more likely to receive training and also received more days of training. Among workers who received training, those with union coverage enjoyed greater returns to training and higher wage growth than did those without. While some of these results have been found in previous studies, others are new. The wage results, in particular, suggest a need for rethinking the conventional view that union wage formation in Britain reduces the incentives to acquire work-related training.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/ilrreview/vol57/iss1/4</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1041&amp;amp;context=ilrreview&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>4</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>1041</articleid>
<submission-date>2005-07-11T10:41:33-07:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>ILR Review</publication-title>
<context-key>82889</context-key>
<submission-path>ilrreview/vol57/iss1/4</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="acknowledgements" type="string">
<value>This research was supported by funds from the Leverhulme Trust under Award F/00213C (“Work-Related Training and Wages of Union and Non-Union Workers in Britain”) and from the Economic and Social Research Council.  For helpful comments, the authors are grateful to Ken Burdett, Ken Chay, Richard Dickens, Gordon Kemp, and seminar participants at the Leverhulme Trust funded joint Essex-Oxford Workshop at the University of Essex, the Education and Employment Economics Group (EEEG) Workshop at the Department for Education and Employment, the CEPR Labor Economics Workshop at Gerzensee, Switzerland, IZA (Bonn), the Australian National University, the London School of Economics, Leicester University, and the 1999 EALE Meetings in Regensberg, Belgium.</value>
</field>
<field name="peer_reviewed" type="boolean">
<value>true</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2003-10-01T00:00:00-07:00</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>