<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>Vol. 3, sec. 2 (pp. 1291-1407). Testimony of porters and sewing machine operators re string on lock in door; extensive arguing between attorneys, December 19-20</title>
<publication-date>1911-12-19T00:00:00-08:00</publication-date>
<authors>
</authors>
<keywords>
<keyword>triangle fire</keyword>
<keyword>levantini</keyword>
<keyword>caliandro</keyword>
<keyword>machine operator</keyword>
<keyword>horton</keyword>
<keyword>porter</keyword>
<keyword>williamson</keyword>
<keyword>mittleman</keyword>
<keyword>employee</keyword>
</keywords>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Vol. 3, sec. 2 (pp. 1291-1407)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MAY CALIANDRO LEVANTINI, machine operator (defendants’ witness, p. 1291); describes actions the day of the fire; describes flames; questioned about lawsuit against Harris &amp; Blanck; questioned about appearance of string on key in door; describes turning key and passing through door; questioned about previous testimony&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long argument between attorneys about access to written testimony&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THOMAS HORTON, porter (defendants’ witness, p. 1325); questioned about previous testimony re lock and door; extensive arguing between attorneys and judge re admissibility of statements&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;REGINALD J. WILLIAMSON, porter, now working for another firm (defendants’ witness, p. 1350); testifies that he took lunch orders from sewing machine operators; describes string on key tied to door-knob, which he himself tied on; testifies about workers dancing to phonograph brought in during strike; about physical layout&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IDA MITTLEMAN, machine operator (defendants’ witness, p. 1371), testifies about where she and her sister sat&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adjourned; resumed December 20, 1911&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IDA MITTLEMAN continues, describes actions the day of the fire, actions of others; still an employee of Harris &amp; Blanck; describes key hanging by string from door-knob; questioned about previous testimony about trying to open the door; long argument between attorneys about access to written testimony&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/triangletrans/9</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1008&amp;amp;context=triangletrans&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>9</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>1008</articleid>
<submission-date>2005-08-24T11:04:06-07:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>Transcripts of Criminal Trial Against Triangle Owners</publication-title>
<context-key>88511</context-key>
<submission-path>triangletrans/9</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="comments" type="string">
<value>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/triangletrans/9</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>1911-12-19T00:00:00-08:00</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>