<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>Analytical Modeling in Complex Surveys of Work Practices</title>
<publication-date>2005-10-01T00:00:00-07:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<institution>Duke University</institution>
<lname>Reiter</lname>
<fname>Jerome</fname>
<mname>P.</mname>
</author>
<author>
<institution>Wharton School at the University of Pennsylvania</institution>
<lname>Zanutto</lname>
<fname>Elaine</fname>
<mname>L.</mname>
</author>
<author>
<institution>University of Wisconsin–Madison</institution>
<lname>Hunter</lname>
<fname>Larry</fname>
<mname>W.</mname>
</author>
</authors>
<keywords>
<keyword>design-based and model-based data analysis</keyword>
</keywords>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Quantitative industrial relations research frequently relies on data collected from large surveys of establishments that use complex sampling designs, such as stratified and unequal probability sampling. The authors analyze two complex surveys of establishments, the National Organizations Survey and the National Survey of Establishments. They discuss design-based (survey-weighted) and model-based (unweighted) strategies for analyzing these data. They show that the choice of strategy can affect inferences about parameters, and hence conclusions drawn from analyses. They discuss the advantages of model-based approaches that include independent variables corresponding to design features, such as functions of size measures or indicator variables for strata or clusters, relative to purely design-based approaches.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/ilrreview/vol59/iss1/5</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1182&amp;amp;context=ilrreview&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>5</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>1182</articleid>
<submission-date>2005-09-23T12:39:51-07:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>ILR Review</publication-title>
<context-key>100382</context-key>
<submission-path>ilrreview/vol59/iss1/5</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="acknowledgements" type="string">
<value>The authors are grateful to Paul Osterman for generously
sharing data from the 1992 National Survey of
Establishments. They also appreciate the help of
Arne Kalleberg and Jerry Jacobs in acquiring and
using the data from the National Organizations Survey.
They thank Jed Frees for his comments.</value>
</field>
<field name="peer_reviewed" type="boolean">
<value>true</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2005-10-01T00:00:00-07:00</value>
</field>
<field name="short_title" type="string">
<value>Analytical Modeling in Complex Surveys of Work Practices</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>