<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>Global Human Resource Metrics</title>
<publication-date>2003-03-01T00:00:00-08:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<institution>Monash University</institution>
<lname>De Cieri</lname>
<fname>Helen</fname>
</author>
<author>
<institution>Cornell University</institution>
<lname>Boudreau</lname>
<fname>John</fname>
<mname>W.</mname>
</author>
</authors>
<keywords>
<keyword>organization</keyword>
<keyword>performance</keyword>
<keyword>research</keyword>
<keyword>employee</keyword>
<keyword>HR</keyword>
<keyword>management</keyword>
<keyword>human resource</keyword>
</keywords>
<disciplines><discipline>Human Resources Management</discipline>
</disciplines><abstract>&lt;p&gt;[Excerpt] What is the logic underlying global human resources (HR) measurement in your organization? In your organization, do you measure the contribution of global HR programs to organizational performance? Do you know what is the most competitive employee mix, e.g., proportion of expatriates vs. local employees, for your business units? (How) do you measure the cost and value of the different types of international work performed by your employees? In the globalized economy, organizations increasingly derive value from human resources, or “talent” as we shall also use the term here (Boudreau, Ramstad &amp; Dowling, in press). The strategic importance of the workforce makes decisions about talent critical to organizational success. Informed decisions about talent require a strategic approach to measurement. However, measures alone are not sufficient, for measures without logic can create information overload, and decision quality rests in substantial part on the quality of measurements. An important element of enhanced global competitiveness is a measurement model for talent that articulates the connections between people and success, as well as the context and boundary conditions that affect those connections. This chapter will propose a framework within which existing and potential global HR measures can be organized and understood. The framework reflects the premise that measures exist to support and enhance decisions, and that strategic decisions require a logical connection between decisions about resources, such as talent, and the key organizational outcomes affected by those decisions. Such a framework may provide a useful mental model for both designers and users of HR measures.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cahrswp/30</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1029&amp;amp;context=cahrswp&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>30</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>1029</articleid>
<submission-date>2005-10-20T11:44:05-07:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>CAHRS Working Paper Series</publication-title>
<context-key>111390</context-key>
<submission-path>cahrswp/30</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="comments" type="string">
<value>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Suggested Citation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;De Cieri, H. &amp; Boudreau, J. W. (2003). &lt;em&gt; Global human resource metrics &lt;/em&gt; (CAHRS Working Paper #03-07). Ithaca, NY: Cornell University, School of Industrial and Labor Relations, Center for Advanced Human Resource Studies. &lt;br /&gt;http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cahrswp/30&lt;/p&gt;</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2003-03-01T00:00:00-08:00</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>